Jongkuk Lee

50 Disera Dr, Toronto, Vaughan, ON L4J9E9 Phone: 416-697-8753. Email: jongkuk.jay.lee@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE: A Java and Angular Developer position where my programming skills and knowledge can contribute to TribalScale Inc.

PROFILE SUMMARY: Worked as a full stack Java/Web developer using Java/J2EE/JavaScript/SQL for 10+ years, completed 20+ large enterprise Java/Web projects, analyzed/designed/documented/developed/tested/deployed Java/Web-based complex business process systems, completed all Angular/RESTful API/NodeJS college projects with A+, engaged in Java component-based development (CBD) and multi-tier model (MVC) projects to raise reusability and scalability

PROFESSIONAL SKILL

Program Language: Java, J2EE/Oracle Business Component for Java (BC4J), JSP (Java Server Page), Servlet, JavaScript (Angular/RESTful API/Node.js/React.js/JQuery/Jasmine/Bootstrap/HTML5/CSS), Structured Query Language (SQL)

IDE (Integration Develop Environment) Tool: StarUML, Borland Together, Eclipse, JDeveloper, SQL Developer,WAS (Web Application Server): Tomcat, Oracle Application Server 10g (Oracle Component for Java), Weblogic

OS (Operate System): Linux, UNIX, Window, IBM i

Product/Framework: Oracle Application Development Framework (OADF)/Oracle Business Component for Java (BC4J), Oracle

MVC-J2EE Framework, POSCO Message-J2EE Framework, Oracle Concurrent Manager on Oracle E-Business

DBMS (Data Base Management System): MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle Database 10g RAC, DB2

Others: Apache ANT (Build tool), Git, Serena PVCS (Version Control), RESORT for Java (Code Checker), LOG4J

EDUCATION

Diploma, Computer Programming Developer

January, 2018

Seneca College

WEB Projects:

Employee Management System (4 months, May, 2017): manages the employees, managers, departments information

- Created a web server using Node.js/Express.js/RESTful API to handle the data on PostgreSQL database
- Created UI pages using the template pages of Handlebars.js
- Created Employee, Department tables on Postgres database
- Verified authentication/authorization on system
- Other key skills: JQuery/AJAX/JSON/Client-session.js/Bootstrap/JavaScript/HTML/CSS

Project Management System (4 months, August, 2017): manages the project information: name, description, leader and so on

- Created the back-end Web API using Node.js/RESTful API to handle the data on MongoDB
- Designed reusable components such as navigation bar, side bar, header, footer, main content component
- Created select/update components using React/Angular to render on UI pages or to use other components
- Tested Unit modules using Jasmine/Angular testing utilities
- Built/Deployed application on Cloud platform (Heroku)
- Other key skills: Express.js/JQuery/AJAX/JSON/SASS/Bootstrap/JavaScript/HTML/CSS

Hyundai Information technology education center 1999

- Java programming language course

BSc. Chemistry March, 1998

Ulsan University

Jongkuk Lee

50 Disera Dr, Toronto, Vaughan, ON L4J9E9 Phone: 416-697-8753. Email: jongkuk.jay.lee@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Job Title	Role	Customer / Region	Period
Manufacturing Execution System (MES) operation	Maintenance Team	POSCO (Korea, Indonesia)	2004~ 2016

Overview: POSCO MES was a Java/J2EE/Oracle solutions/Web-based system to automate POSCO steelwork manufacturing lines including over 200 factories and connected with PLC/process computing and ERP system

Key responsibilities:

- Worked as a member of POSCO MES maintenance team.
- Analyzed/designed/documented/developed/tested the Java and SQL-based source codes according to the customers' service requests of 4 factories in Korea and 1 factory in Indonesia, to improve the systems and enhance business processes
- Monitored/debugged system faults in remote-area using VPN software to support 24/7 non-stop system
- Responded the queries of the maintenance team managers in a very short period of time
- Reported the impacts of the system changes to support the system project teams

Key skills: Java/J2EE/JSP/Servlet/JavaScript/Business Component for Java/Oracle MVC-J2EE framework/POSCO Message-J2EE Framework/Structured Query Language (SQL)/Oracle Database 10g RAC/Oracle Concurrent Manager on Oracle E-Business

POSPIA 3.0 Developing Team POSCO (Korea, Indonesia) 2013~20

Overview: POSPIA3.0 was a Java/J2EE/Oracle solutions/Web-based system to track the raw materials, products, and costs in POSCO global workplaces through standardization of over 170 global business systems like ERP, MES, and SCM

Key responsibilities:

- Analyzed/designed/documented/developed/tested the Java/SQL-based source codes of manufacturing system related to changing POSCO ERP model to contribute accurately calculation of product cost information
- Extracted business process rules from the Java source codes of the manufacturing system to manage on centralized data repositories for standardization of product information called "a master data system"
- Provided SQL query statements for dashboard on Oracle Business Intelligence to compare between MES and ERP system
- Engaged in the tests for new Java-based systems following to construct a new steelwork in Indonesia

Key skills: JSP/Servlet/Java/J2EE/Business Component for Java/Oracle MVC-J2EE framework/POSCO Message-J2EE Framework/Structured Query Language (SQL)/Oracle Database 10g RAC/Oracle Concurrent Manager on Oracle E-Business/Oracle Process Manufacturing (OPM), Oracle Business Intelligence

Manufacturing System Renovation Developing Team POSCO (Korea) 2002~ 2004

Overview: POSCO MES Renovation project was a part of POSCO Process Innovation (PI) activities, and it was the first enterprise solution to be applied Java/J2EE to large-scale process manufacturing system

Kev responsibilities:

- Created UI pages to back up when the automation system was unavailable, using Oracle Java/J2EE solutions such as Oracle Application Development Framework (OADF), Oracle MVC-J2EE Framework, and Oracle Business Component for Java
- Created NON-UI applications to send/receive data among automation sensor (PLC) /process computing (P/C) ~ Business computing (B/C) ~ ERP, using POSCO Message-J2EE Framework built based, and EAI server
- Developed statistics reports/charts using Java/J2EE/Oracle Concurrent Manager, and Oracle Database to detect risks
- Developed real-time monitoring pages to track the raw materials and products to reduce the bottle neck

Key skills: Java/J2EE/Applet/JClass chart/JSP/Servlet/JavaScript/Business Component for Java/Oracle MVC-J2EE framework/POSCO Message-J2EE Framework/Structured Query Language (SQL)/Oracle Database 10g RAC/Oracle Concurrent Manager on Oracle E-Business/Enterprise Application Integration (EAI: Fiorano solution and U-Cube)

POSCO Other Projects: System Designer/System Developer/Java, J2EE, JSP, Servlet, JavaScript, BC4J, OC4J, Oracle

- Steel Plate System Refine (2015), New Steel Plate Product Computerization (2014), Product Quality Detect System (2012),
- Steel Plate New Cutting Line Computerization (2011), Steel Plate New Heat Treatment Line Computerization (2007),
- Ethics Declaration System (2006), Financial Audit System (2005) Hot coil Factory Computerization (2004) and so on

Other Company Projects:

- Mileage Integration System (Hyundai Department Store, Korea, 2001) Developer/JSP, Java, EJB, Oracle, Weblogic, UNIX
- Stock Website Renovation (Sejong Stock Exchange, Korea, 2001) Developer/built stock charts using Java/JClass solutions
- Customer Relation Management (CRM) System (Hitachi System, Japan, 2000) Developer/JSP, Java, Jserve, HiRDB, UNIX
- Web Recruiting System (Tomato, Korea, 2000) Developer/ASP, Visual Basic, IIS, Visual Studio, MS-SQL, Window NT
- Web Portal Site (Korea Digital Manager Association, Korea, 2000) Developer JSP, Java, Tomcat, Oracle, Linux and so on